So we're now going to look at four bit quantization, the rather remarkable effect of reducing the precision
이제 4비트 퀀타이즈를 살펴볼 겁니다 정밀도를 끝까지 낮추는 놀라운
all the way down.
효과죠
So very similar to before we create a quant config using bits and bytes.
비트와 바이트를 이용한 퀀트 구성 이전과 아주 유사하죠
But this time we asked to load in four bit equals.
하지만 이번엔 4 비트 =으로 로드하라고 했죠
True.
맞아요
There are some other settings here too.
다른 설정도 있어요
This time there's one called use double Quant, which again is slightly mysterious.
이번엔 더블 퀀트 사용이란 게 있는데 이것도 살짝 수수께끼죠
The idea here is that it does a pass through quantizing all of the weights, and then it does a second
모든 무게를 수량화해서 통과하게 하는 거예요 그리고 다시
pass through again.
한번 통과하죠
And in doing so it's able to reduce memory by I think about 10 to 20% more.
그렇게 함으로써 메모리를 10에서 20퍼센트 더 줄일 수 있어요
It squeezes a bit more out of this.
비트를 더 짜내는 거예요
And this is, uh, experimentally shown to make it very, very small difference to the power of the
그리고 이건 실험적으로 입증된 건데 신경망의 힘에 아주 미세한 차이를 만들어냈어요
So it's almost a freebie.
거의 공짜나 다름없죠
It's again cake and eat it situation.
둘 다 해당하는 상황이죠
So recommended to use Double Quant as true.
그래서 더블 퀀트를 참으로 사용하라고 권장했죠
This here compute dtype is about the data type that's used during computation.
계산 dtype은 계산에 사용되는 데이터 타입에 관한 거죠
And there generally you could work with 32 bit floats here.
일반적으로 32 비트 플로트로 작업할 수 있어요
But using the Bfloat16 data type binary float 16 is seen as something which improves the speed of training
Bfloat16 데이터 유형의 플로트 이진법 16을 사용하면 훈련
and makes it faster, with only a tiny sacrifice to quality of the of the training.
속도가 빨라집니다 훈련의 질을 조금만 희생해도요
Certainly when I've tried this, I've seen it run faster and I've not been able to detect any actual
확실히 제가 이걸 시도했을 땐 더 빨리 실행되는 걸 봤어요 최적화 속도에서
change in the rate of of of optimization.
실제적인 변화는 감지할 수 없었죠
So this is recommended for sure.
그러니 이건 확실히 추천해요
But again, it's a hyper parameter that you can experiment with.
하지만 이것도 하이퍼 매개 변수라 실험할 수 있어요
And then this here the the four bit quant type.
이건 4 비트 퀀트 유형이에요
This is saying when we reduce the precision down to a four bit number, how should we interpret that
4 비트 숫자로 정밀도를 낮출 때 4 비트 숫자를 어떻게 해석해야
four bit number.
할까요?
You might think okay, so if it's four bits 0000 through to 1111, then that represents an integer from
4bit00부터 1111까지라고 하면 0부터 15까지 정수라고 생각할
0 to 15.
수도 있죠
That might be one way of doing it.
그것도 한 방법이죠
Um it's more common to interpret it, map it to a sort of a floating point number.
부동점 숫자에 맞춰 지도를 만드는 게 일반적이죠
Um, and this nf4 approach maps it to something which has a normal distribution to it.
이 nf4 접근법은 정규 배포된 뭔가에 매핑해요
And so again, this is very common setting.
이건 아주 흔한 설정이에요
Uh, it's what I've used.
제가 쓴 거예요
I tried something else and it wasn't as good.
다른 걸 해 봤는데 별로였어요
So so this is the generally the recommended one.
일반적으로 권장하는 게 이거죠
But it is a hyper parameter which means it is yours for trial and error.
하이퍼 매개 변수라서 시행착오를 겪어도 사용 가능해요
With that in mind, we create this quant config, which is very standard quant config for four bit quantization.
그걸 염두에 두고 퀀트 구성을 만드는데 4비트 퀀트화를 위한 아주 표준적인 퀀트 구성이죠
And we create a base model with that which I have done and will now print the memory footprint.
기본 모델을 생성합니다 메모리 공간을 프린트할 거예요
And remarkably, we are down to 5.6GB.
놀랍게도 현재는 5마리로 줄었죠 6GB요
You may have already spotted that over here in my resources, but when you remember that the base model,
제 리소스에서 이미 보셨을 수도 있지만 기본 모델을 기억하시면
the real thing was 32GB in size, it's really come a long way down.
실제 크기는 32GB였죠 정말 많이 줄었어요
So this is now something which will comfortably fit in our GPU's memory for this cheap T4 box.
이 정도면 GPU 메모리에 저렴한 T4 박스에 쉽게 들어갈 거예요
And if we look at the base model, we'll see the architecture.
기본 모델을 보면 아키텍처가 있어요
I'm not going to try and make that stupid joke again.
그 멍청한 농담은 다시 안 할 거예요
It is, of course, identical to the architecture of the original, beefier 8 billion llama model.
물론 더 우람했던 80억 라마 모델의 구조와 동일하죠
Just that within this deep within this, the precision of the weights is lower.
이 깊숙한 곳에서는 무게추의 정확도가 낮아요
It's four bit.
4비트예요
Okay.
네
In the next video, at this point, you should not restart your session.
다음 비디오에선 이 시점에서 세션을 다시 시작하지 마세요
We need to keep this session as it is, and in the next video we're going to go in and load in our example
이번 세션은 이대로 유지해야 합니다 다음 비디오에선 미세 조정 모델의 예제를 불러오겠습니다
of a fine tuned model and see how the Laura adaptations apply to this architecture.
로라가 적응한 것이 이 구조에 어떻게 적용되는지 보죠
I'll see you there.
거기서 봐요